Guide to the Teunis G. Bergen and Bergen family collection ARC.006
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Group 1: Teunis G. Bergen papers
  - Series 6: Personal papers, 1747-1881; 0.2 Linear Feet in one manuscript box
    - Bergen, Teunis G. - Photographic portrait, circa 1860-1880 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Bergen vs. Gulner, circa 1876 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Bogart, Peter - Estate papers, 1871, 1877-1878 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Bonds, 1836-1876 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Elizabeth Brainerd and Catherine Barr - Last Wills and Testaments, circa 19th century (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Brooklyn Bureau of Charities: Annual report, circa 19th century (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Brooklyn & Flatbush Turnpike: Court decision on ownership, 1867 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Carriage house plans, circa 19th century (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Catalog of books in Teunis Bergen's library, circa 1850-1881 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Catherine and Main Street Ferry - Broadside, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Cholera Epidemic - Article from the Board of Health, 1832 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Commissioner of Records, 1856-1875 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Common Council: Street Committee report, 1848 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Congressional Representative: Certificates, 1864, 1867 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1826-1859 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence (official), 1828-1859 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1832-1880 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (incoming), 1845-1877 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1881 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence (outgoing), 1861-1868 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Court papers, 1839, 1849 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Cultivator subscription list, 1839-1861 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Deeds, nd (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Deeds and conveyances, 1747-1879 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Drafts of legal agreements, 1841-1865 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Dutch records translation (misc.), circa 19th century (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Dutch records translation (New Utrecht), circa 19th century (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Dutch translations published in the Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1874 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Early Settlers of King's County: Subscription list, ca. 1880 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Garretson, G.R.: Price List for Seeds, 1863-1865 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Gashire, Judith: Narrative (translation from Dutch, 1766), circa 19th century (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Historical narrative - Brooklyn tide mills, circa 1830-1881 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Historical narrative - The Old De Hart or Bergen house, circa 1830-1881 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Leases, 1832-1869 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - List of persons to whom lots assessed, 1849 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Memorial for Teunis Bergen by Henry C. Murphy, 1881 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Military papers, 1829, 1836-1837 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1834-1880 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1835, 1837-1838 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Mortgages, 1835, 1837-1838 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Newspapers, 1856-1879 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - New Jersey Farm (Keyport), 1857-1860 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - New York State Convention, 1846, 1854, 1860 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Obituary (from Brooklyn Daily Eagle), April 25, 1881 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Plans for the building of a sailboat, 1845 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Provincial Convention - Elected delegates from Kings County, 1775 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Receipts, 1843-1858 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Report of the Committee Concerning the grading of 3rd Avenue between Bay Ridge and Fort Hamilton, 1861 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Road List, District No. 4, 1855 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - St. Nicholas Society, 1862, 1878 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - School books, 1815-1816 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - School books, 1818 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - School books, 1819 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - School books, 1820-1823 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Seating plan of the U.S. House of Representatives and Senate, circa 1860s (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Stocks, 1869, 1872 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Survey book, 1869 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Surveys, 1850-1870 ca. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Table of distances from Brooklyn City Hall, circa 1830-1881 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Table of feet and inches in chains and links, circa 1830-1881 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Travel journals, 1856-1857; 1862 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Van Pelt family - Estate papers, 1856-1861; 1876 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Whitman, Walt - Correspondence to Teunis G. Bergen, 1849, 1851; 2 Linear Feet in 5 boxes. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Series 7: Surveying records, 1704-1877; 4.6 Linear Feet in 11 boxes.
    Surveying records is organized into seven subseries and documents the various duties carried out by Teunis G. Bergen as a surveyor. The series is comprised primarily of maps and surveys of land owned by residents of Brooklyn and its environs, as well as roads and streets in the area, providing a glimpse into the evolution of Brooklyn's geography and physical infrastructure in the mid-to-late 19th century. Also included are drafts of legal documents, including deeds and legal land descriptions; building specifications of houses in Brooklyn; notes and calculations recorded by Bergen in the course of his surveying work; and title searches undertaken by Bergen to support his surveying work. The series is organized into seven subseries: Bound surveys; Drafts of legal documents; Field notes and calculations; Maps and surveys; Map tracings and land descriptions; Specifications of houses; and Title searches. Subseries 1 is comprised of five bound and numbered volumes, arranged in numerical order. Subseries 2, 3, 5, 6, and 7 are arranged alphabetically according to the personal name of a propert owner or the property's name. Subseries 4 is organized alphabetically by neighborhood name, and thereafter by the property owner's name.
    - Subseries 1: Bound surveys, circa 1850s
      - Books 1-3, circa 1850s (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Books 4 & 5, circa 1850s (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Subseries 2: Drafts of legal documents, 1845-1881
      - Barre, Ann, circa 19th century (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Belson, 1872 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Bennet, Charles C., 1878-1880 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Bennet, Clarence E., 1878 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Bennet, Cornelius, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Bennet, Gertrude, 1834, 1841 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Bennet, J.R., 1868 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Bennet, John C., 1856 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Bennet, John J., circa 1840-1880 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Bennet, R.R., 1853-1865 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Bennet, W.E., 1872 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Bennet, W.W., 1864, 1881 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Bennet, William, 1860, 1868, 1881 (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Bennet, Winant, 1853-1854, 1857 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Bergen, Cornelius, circa 19th century (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Bergen, Elizabeth, 1857 (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Bergen, Garret, 1859 (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Bergen, Joanna, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - Bergen, John, 1853-1854 (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Bergen, Lefferts, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - Bergen, Teunis, 1856, 1859 (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - Board of Supervisors, 1859 (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - Bogert, Peter, 1856, 1877, 1880 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - Boyle, W.H., 1858 (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Carson, Deorah, 1854, 1858-1859, 1863 (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Cowenhoven, Annette, 1855-1856 (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - Cowenhoven, Cornelius, 1881 (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - Cowenhoven, Garret, 1856 (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - Cowenhoven, Nicholas, 1866, 1873 (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - Cowenhoven, Peter, 1854 (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Cowenhoven, Phebe, nd, 1859 (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - Cropsey, Andrew, 1873 (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - Delaplaine, John, 1840 (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Denyse, Tunis, 1853 (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - Duryea, Abraham & Maria, 1855 (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - Emmans, J.A., 1853, 1870, 1873, 1877 (Box 23, Folder 38)
      - Furman, Z., 1853 (Box 23, Folder 39)
      - Gelston, G.S., 1853 (Box 23, Folder 40)
      - Gravesend & Flatbush (Boundary Line), circa 19th century (Box 23, Folder 41)
      - Hart, John, circa 19th century (Box 23, Folder 42)
      - Hayman, John, 1858 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Hendrickson, J.B., 1856 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Hubbard, Samuel, 1853 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Hunt, Thomas, 1855 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Johnson, Jerome, 1856 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Kent, H.A., 1864, 1873 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Kouwenhoven, George, 1878 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Kouwenhoven, William J., 1856 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Langley, William, 1879 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Lefferts, John, 1856 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Lefferts, Robert B., 1855 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Lott, Charles, 1856, 1875 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Lott, Englebert & Jeremiah, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Lott, Jeremiah, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Magaw, Lawrence, 1879 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Monfort, Andrew, 1879 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Pope, P. Bennet, 1863-1864 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Prince, Charles, 1853, 1856 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Rea, W.F., 1853, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Reformed Protestant Dutch Church (New Utrecht), 1872 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Schenck, Jeremiah, 1857 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Sedgwick, Theodore, 1880 (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Stanton, Alexander, 1858 (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Stanton, Henry, 1853, 1858 (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Stillwell, Coert, 1868 (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - Stillwell, George, 1864, 1877 (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - Stillwell, Henry, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - Stillwell, Jaques, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - Stillwell, John, 1855 (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - Stillwell, Nicholas, 1861 (Box 24, Folder 29)
      - Stillwell, Phebe, 1859 (Box 24, Folder 30)
      - Stillwell, Richard, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 31)
      - Stryker Family, 1854, 1857 (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - Stryker, S.S., 1864 (Box 24, Folder 33)
      - Suydam, Tunis, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 34)
      - Unidentifiable Names, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 35)
      - Van Blankenstein, 1873 (Box 24, Folder 36)
      - Van Brunt, Albert, 1853, 1875 (Box 24, Folder 37)
      - Van Brunt, Daniel, 1865, 1874-1879 (Box 24, Folder 38)
      - Van Brunt, George, 1877, 1880 (Box 24, Folder 39)
      - Van Brunt, Jacques, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 40)
      - Van Brunt, Rulif, nd (Box 24, Folder 41)
      - Van Pelt, 1858, 1876 (Box 24, Folder 42)
      - Van Sicklen, circa 19th century (Box 24, Folder 43)
      - Vanderbilt, John J., 1854 (Box 24, Folder 44)
      - Voorhees, Jacques & Jacobus, 1873 (Box 24, Folder 45)
      - Voorhees, John J., 1854 (Box 24, Folder 46)
      - Wardell, Simon G., 1859 (Box 24, Folder 47)
      - Wyckoff, B., 1845 (Box 24, Folder 48)
      - Wyckoff, H.R., 1868 (Box 24, Folder 49)
      - Wycoff, John & George, 1860 (Box 24, Folder 50)
      - Wyckoff, Peter, 1872 (Box 24, Folder 51)
      - Wyckoff, Van Brunt, 1856 (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Subseries 3: Field notes and calculations, 1842-1870
      - Bath Property (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Bennet, C. (Gowanus), 1842 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Bennet, Christopher (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Bennet, Joseph, James & John, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Bennet, Michael & John (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Bennet, R.R. (Fort Hamilton), 1863 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Bennet, William, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Bennet, Winant, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Bergen, Jane (Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Bergen, John C. (Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Bergen, Leffert, 1853 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Bergen, Teunis G. (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Bergen, Theodorus, 1853 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Bergen, Theodorus & Johnson, Coert (New Utrecht), 1845 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Botanical Garden (8th Ward, Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Clarkson, M., 1865 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Clute (Fort Hamilton), 1857 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Copeland, Edward, 1861 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Cornell, L., circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Cortelyou (at the Narrows), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Cow Lane (Flatbush), 1855 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Cowenhoven, Garret, 1855 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - Cowenhoven, Johannes, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Cowenhoven, Phebe (New Utrecht), 1852 (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Cowenhoven & Backhouse, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - Crooke, P.S., 1851, 1853 (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - Cropsey, Jaques W., circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - Cropsey, Valentine, 1842, 1854 (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Cummings, Robert (Fort Hamilton), 1858 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - De Russey, 1855 (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - Degroff, Abraham (New Utrecht), 1852 (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - Delaplaine (New Utrecht), 1852 (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - Denyse (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - Dyker Meadows, 1863 (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Emmans, Andrew, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 35)
      - Emmans, J.A. & Lindley, John, 1860 (Box 25, Folder 36)
      - Flatbush Avenue, 1854, 1858 (Box 25, Folder 37)
      - Flatbush & New Lots (Boundary Line), 1852 (Box 25, Folder 38)
      - Flatbush & New Utrecht Plank Road, 1852 (Box 25, Folder 39)
      - Fourth Avenue, 1869 (Box 25, Folder 40)
      - Garretson, Elsie & Bergen, Michael, nd (Box 25, Folder 41)
      - Geltson, George S. (Fort Hamilton), 1852-1853 (Box 25, Folder 42)
      - Gravesend Plank Road, 1853 (Box 25, Folder 43)
      - Griswold, Zachariah (Bay Ridge), 1855, 1857 (Box 25, Folder 44)
      - Grove, George & Benson, Egbert (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 45)
      - Hamilton Avenue, 1855 (Box 25, Folder 46)
      - Higgins, circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 47)
      - Hubbard, Samuel & Stryker, G. (Gravesend), 1853 (Box 25, Folder 48)
      - Hunt & Dalaphine, nd (Box 25, Folder 49)
      - Kent, H.A., circa 1830-1881 (Box 25, Folder 50)
      - Kings County Alms House, 1858, 1862 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Lefferts, John (Flatbush), 1853, 1855 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Lefferts, Leffert Property (New Utrecht), 1850-1852 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Lefferts, Robert (New Utrecht), 1867 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Lott, John A. (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Lunatic Asylum (Flatbush), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Martense, Garret (Flatbush), 1852 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Martense, George, 1859 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - McGrath, circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Middle Street to 19th Street, 1850 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Murphy, Aaron, circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Murphy, Thomas (Gravesend), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - New Utrecht, circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - New Utrecht, 1851, 1854 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - New Utrecht (2nd & 4th Avenues), 1869 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Ovington Avenue, 1852 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Ovington, William A. (Yellow Hook), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Penetentiary to Alms House (Grade Lines of Road), 1857 (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Post Farm, circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Prince, C., circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - Richards, Daniel (Yellow Hook), 1852-1854 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Road from Gravesend to Brooklyn, 1846-1849 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Rodgers Avenue (near Penitentiary), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Ryder, Lawrence (Flatlands), 1858 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Second Avenue, 1870 (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - Stillwell, John (New Utrecht), 1855 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Stillwell, N., circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Stillwell Family (Gravesend), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - Stryker Family (Gravesend), 1857 (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - Suydam, Evert (New Utrecht), 1858 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Talmage, Thomas G. (Brooklyn), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - Third Avenue (Bay Ridge to Fort Hamilton), 1860 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      - Trumbull Estate, circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 33)
      - Twenty-Second Avenue, circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - United States (Government Land at Fort Hamilton), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 35)
      - Vanderbilt, Jeremiah (Flatbush), 1854 (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - Van Brunt, N.R. (near Bath), 1846 (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - Van Pelt, Henry, 1846 (Box 26, Folder 38)
      - Van Pelt, John (Brooklyn), 1852 (Box 26, Folder 39)
      - White, Matilda, 1860 (Box 26, Folder 40)
      - Wyckoff, P. (New Utrecht), circa 1830-1881 (Box 26, Folder 41)
      - Yellow Hook, 1851 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Subseries 4: Maps and surveys, 1704-1879
      - Bay Ridge, nd
        - Mackay, John, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - McGee, Owen, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Van Brunt, Albert, 1875 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Brooklyn and Bushwick, 1704-1879
        - Anderson & Clark, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 4)
        - Barr Estate (Near Prospect Park), 1876 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Bedford Avenue, 1844 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        - Bennet, William (copy), 1696 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Bennet, Winant (copy), 1696 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Bergen Burial Ground, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - Bergen, Derick, 1781 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - Bergen, Garret, 1839 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - Bergen, George, 1737 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - Bergen, Garret P., 1844 (Box 27, Folder 13)
        - Bergen, Hans, 1728, 1763 (Box 27, Folder 14)
        - Bergen, Jacob, 1750 (Box 27, Folder 15)
        - Bergen, Jane, 1853 (Box 27, Folder 16)
        - Bergen, John C., 1855 (Box 27, Folder 17)
        - Bergen, John S., circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 18)
        - Bergen, Lefferts, 1854 (Box 27, Folder 19)
        - Bergen, Michael, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 20)
        - Bergen, Michael J., 1863 (Box 27, Folder 21)
        - Bergen, Michael Hansen, 1723 (Box 27, Folder 22)
        - Bergen, Theodorus, 1850, 1853 (Box 27, Folder 23)
        - Berry, Rachel, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 24)
        - Bompjes Hook, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 25)
        - Bowren, Watson, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 26)
        - Brooklyn Penitentiary, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 27)
        - Brooklyn Woodlands (copy), 1874 (Box 27, Folder 28)
        - Carson, Deborah, circa 1850-1865 (Box 27, Folder 29)
        - Clark & Anderson, 1851 (Box 27, Folder 30)
        - Cortelyou, Isaac, 1842 (Box 27, Folder 31)
        - Crooke, Margaret & P.S., circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 32)
        - DeBevoise, James, 1849 (Box 27, Folder 33)
        - Delaplaine, John, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 34)
        - Delaplaine & Morris, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 35)
        - Ditmas, Henry S., 1846 (Box 27, Folder 36)
        - Eighth Ward Farmland, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 37)
        - Forble, Saul & Delaplain, circa 1830-1881 (Box 27, Folder 38)
        - Gowanus Cove, 1854-1855 (Box 27, Folder 39)
        - Greenwood Cemetery, 1844, 1853-1854 (Box 27, Folder 40)
        - Hunt, Thomas, 1844-1846, 1851 (Box 27, Folder 41)
        - Hussey, George, 1860 (Box 27, Folder 42)
        - Kent, Henry, 1846, 1873 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Lake, Johnson, 1846, 1849, 1851 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Lefferts, John, 1855 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Lott, Christopher, circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Lott, Jacobus, 1843-1844 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Lott, James, 1849 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - Lott, Johannes, circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - Martense, George, 1868 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Matbone, R., circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Morris, Leah, 1854 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Morris, Leah, 1867 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Ninth Ward, 1846 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - Pope, Henry, 1848, 1864 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - Powers Farm, 1723 (Box 28, Folder 14)
        - Property between 50th & 51st Streets and 7th Avenue, circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 15)
        - Rapalje, Johannes, 1769 (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - Ridgewood Park, 1868 (Box 28, Folder 17)
        - Rockwell, William, 1839, 1841 (Box 28, Folder 18)
        - Ryerson Family, 1851 (Box 28, Folder 19)
        - Saul, Jonathan, 1844 (Box 28, Folder 20)
        - Schermerhorn, Abraham, 1761 (Box 28, Folder 21)
        - Sixth Ward, Circa 1800s (Box 28, Folder 22)
        - Smith, Samuel, 1851 (Box 28, Folder 23)
        - Spear, Calvin, 1842-1843 (Box 28, Folder 24)
        - Stone & Sother, 1849 (Box 28, Folder 25)
        - Stout, William, 1865 (Box 28, Folder 26)
        - Stryker, Michael, 1863 (Box 28, Folder 27)
        - Suydam, Hencrick, 1848 (Box 28, Folder 28)
        - Suydam, Tunis, 1865 (Box 28, Folder 29)
        - Thomas, Robert W., 1853 (Box 28, Folder 30)
        - Unidentifiable property, circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 31)
        - Van Brunt, Adrian, circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 32)
        - Van Brunt, Albert, 1846, 1857, 1876, 1846-1876 (Box 28, Folder 33)
        - Vanderbilt, John, 1843, 1852 (Box 28, Folder 34)
        - Vandervoort, 1845 (Box 28, Folder 35)
        - Van Pelt, Henry, 1846 (Box 28, Folder 36)
      - East New York, 1859
        - Pitkin, G.D., 1859 (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - Flatbush, 1855-1874, nd
        - Clarkson Street lots (copy), 1831 (Box 28, Folder 38)
        - Linden Terrace, circa 1830-1881 (Box 28, Folder 39)
        - Murphy, Thomas, 1871-1872 (Box 28, Folder 40)
        - Robertson, 1855 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Turner Brothers, 1874 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - Vanderveer, Henry, 1864 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Flatlands, 1747-1875
        - Baldwin, Abigail, 1853 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Baldwin Property, circa 1830-1881 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Boundary Line Between Flatlands and Gravesend, 1856 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Canarsie, Public Landing Road, 1872 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - Catin, Susan, 1845 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - Church Land - Reformed Dutch Church (copy), 1747 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        - Clarkson, Matthew, 1843 (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - Kowenhoven Family, 1845-1875 (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - Remsen, John, 1842-1843 (Box 29, Folder 12)
        - Ryder, Lawrence, 1858 (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - Schenck, Jeremiah, 1857 (Box 29, Folder 14)
        - Stoothoff Family, 1842 (Box 29, Folder 15)
        - Terhune, John, 1842 (Box 29, Folder 16)
        - Van Dyke, Nicholas, 1850 (Box 29, Folder 17)
        - Van Houten, Rulif, 1854 (Box 29, Folder 18)
        - Voorhees, Jacob, 1849 (Box 29, Folder 19)
        - Waldron, Cornelius, 1846 (Box 29, Folder 20)
        - Williamson, John, 1843 (Box 29, Folder 21)
        - Wyckoff, Garret, 1849 (Box 29, Folder 22)
        - Wyckoff, Henry, circa 1830-1881 (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - Fort Hamilton, 1874, nd
        - Muspratt, John, circa 1830-1881 (Box 29, Folder 24)
        - Denyse, John, 1835 (Box 29, Folder 25)
        - Post, William, 1874 (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - Gravesend, 1839-1853, nd
        - Bennet, Cornelius, 1845 (Box 29, Folder 27)
        - Emmans, Johannes, 1847 (Box 29, Folder 28)
        - Madaw, Van Brunt, 1839 (Box 29, Folder 29)
        - Propsed Highway Between Gravesend, New Utrecht and Flatbush, circa 1830-1881 (Box 29, Folder 30)
        - Ryder, John, circa 1830-1881 (Box 29, Folder 31)
        - Stillwell, Richard R., 1850 (Box 29, Folder 32)
        - Terhune Estate, 1853 (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - New Lots, 1850-1866